So the empty list of dictionaries,
空白的字典名单
df_list, is already there for you,
df_list 已经提供给你
as well as the for loop that loops through every file in our rt_html folder.
以及在我们 rt_html 文件夹中循环每个文件的 for 循环
The first thing to do is make the soup,
要做的第一件事是就是制作 soup
which we do by passing in the file handle file,
我们的方法是将文件传递至文件句柄中
or whatever you named your file handle.
或者你给文件句柄起的任何名称
The first thing to grab from the HTML was the title,
从 HTML 中抓取的第一个对象就是名称
the movie title, which was already done previously.
电影名称 这件事我们之前已经完成过
Again, using the find method to get the only title tag in the document,
再次使用 find 法获得文档中的唯一名称标签
then accessing the contents of that file using.contents,
然后利用 .contents 访问该文件的内容
and grabbing the first item in that tag and slicing off that last ' - Rotten Tomatoes'.
抓取标签中的第一个项目 截取最后的 ‘- Rotten Tomatoes’
Let's take a look here and debug a bit,
我们来看下 稍加调试
just in case something has gone wrong.
以免有任何部分出错
So we'll loop through this loop once,
所以 我们再使用这个循环一次
then print out the title variable as we have it here,
然后 打出我们在这里具有的名称变量
then break from the loop.
然后 中断循环
This is good practice. Okay, and there's the title.
这就是规范做法 好的 名称得到了
I actually forgot to specify the lxml parser,
实际上我忘了指定 lxml 解析器
which is actually okay, but I'll specify it anyways.
其实这样也没关系 但我还是会指定它的
Okay, there we go, no warning.
好的 我们现在就开始 没有警告
The next thing to grab was the audience_score.
下一个要抓取的对象是 audience_score
Let's take a look at our HTML code to see where that's at.
我们来看看 HTML 代码 看看它在哪里
So there's that 72% and it's actually within
在 72% 处 它确实在
a div with the class titled audience-score meter.
class 名称为 audience-score meter 的 div 内部
If you look closer, you'll see that the 72% is
如果再仔细看下 你就会发现 72%
within the only span tag within this outermost div tag,
在最外侧 div 标签内的唯一一个 span 标签中
the outermost one being this div with,
最外侧的 div 标签就是这个 div
again, the class audience-score meter.
其 class 就是 audience-score meter
Because it's the first span tag,
由于它是第一个 span 标签
we can use the.find method,
我们可以使用 .find 方法
a beautiful soup, to get the first tag of whatever tag we search using find.
它是一个 beautiful soup 以获得我们利用 find 搜索的任意标签中的第一个标签
But first, we'll actually have to identify the div with the class audience-score meter,
但首先 我们必须识别 class 为 audience-score meter 的 div
which is done like so.
这也是采用类似方法完成的
Note that class has to have an underscore after it.
请注意 class 的后面必须有一个下划线
That's because class is a reserved key word in Python.
这是因为 class 是 Python 中的一个保留关键词
And we'll find this first span tag within this div and
我们将找到这个 div 中的第一个 span 标签
lt's just take a break here again and look where we're at with this code.
现在我们稍稍休息一下 看看我们讲到代码的哪个部分了
We'll loop through this code once,
我们将再使用循环一次
print out the audience score,
打出 audience score
then break from the loop again. Okay, it's all looking good.
然后再次中断循环 好的 这一切看起来很顺利
It will access the contents of this tag
它将使用 .contents 访问该标签的内容
using.contents and because it's the first and only item within this tag,
而且由于它是这个标签中的第一个 也是唯一一个项目
we'll use the 0 index, i.e.
所以 我们使用索引 0 即
the first item of the list returned from.contents, and we're almost there.
.contents 返回的名单中的第一个项目 我们马上就讲到那里了
We actually don't want this percentage sign.
我们实际上并不想要这个百分比符号
So, we'll get rid of that with some basic string slicing.
所以 我们将利用基本的字符串截取功能去除它
Grabbing everything in the string except the last character in it, and great.
抓取字符串中除最后一个字符以外的所有字符 很好
We've got our audience score.
我们就得到观众评分了
Now, to grab the number of audience ratings.
现在 该抓取观众评分的数量了
This one's a bit more complicated.
这个有点复杂
Let's take a peek at the HTML code once again.
我们再看下 HTML 代码
If we scroll down a bit, we'll see the user ratings
如果我们向下滚动一点 我们就会见到用户评分
here or the number of audience ratings.
或观众评分数量了
This is for the E.T.
这适用于电影《ET 外星人》 HTML 页面
movie HTML page, but this structure applies to all of the files we downloaded.
但这个结构适用于我们下载的所有文件
So, it's a bit hard to see here,
所以 在这里 虽然不是太清楚
but the outermost div tag is this one here with
但最外侧的 div 标签就是
the class audience-info hidden-xs superPageFontColor.
class 为 audience-info hidden-xs superPageFontColor 的这个标签
So let's zoom in on that using BeautifulSoup.
所以 我们利用 BeautifulSoup 来放大它
That's quite a bit to type out, so I'll copy and paste this here.
敲出来太麻烦 所以我复制粘贴到这里
Again, let's use the loop and print and break strategy.
我们再次使用循环、显示和中断策略
That's a bit more clear.
这样就更清晰一些了
Here's the outermost div with the class we specified,
这就是我们所指定 class 的最外侧 div
audience-info hidden-xs superPageFontColor,
audience-info hidden-xs superPageFontColor
and within that div tag is two other div tags,
该 div 标签内有两个其他的 div 标签
and the number of audience ratings is in the second div tag.
观众评分的数量在第二个 div 标签内
We can use find all and take the second item in that returned list.
我们可以使用 find all 选取返回名单中的第二个项目
The second item being index number 1.
第二个项目就是索引数字 1
Then if we look at the contents here,
接着 如果我们看看这里的内容
we'll see our number of audience ratings,
我们会见到我们的观众评分数量
third item index number 2.
第三个项目索引数字 2
There's a bunch of white space here we'll strip out using the Python strip function,
这里有一连串的白色空格 我们将使用 Python strip 函数剔除它
and we're almost done.
我们几乎完成了
This is currently in string form.
目前这就是字符串形式
We'll later have to convert to an integer and to do that,
我们稍后必须转换成整数 为此
we'll actually have to remove these commas.
我们必须删除这些逗号
So, we'll do that using Python's replace function,
所以 我们使用 Python replace 函数来做这件事
replacing commas with the empty character.
用空字符替换逗号
And there we go and now,
我们马上开始
all that's left to do is convert our list of dictionaries,
接下来要做的就是将我们的字典名单
df_list, to a Pandas dataframe.
df_list 转换成一个 Pandas DataFrame
First, we'll make sure that the Pandas library is imported and aliased as PD,
首先 我们将确保 Pandas 库已导入 且别名为 PD
and we'll specify the column order,
接着 我们将指定列序号
and that should be it.
应该是这样
Let's process this cell.
我们来处理这个单元格
This may take a bit of time to run.
这运行起来可能需要花费一点时间
For me, around 15 seconds or so.
对我而言 大约 15 秒钟左右
And great, no errors.
非常好 没有错误
Let's take a look at this dataframe.
我们来看看这个 DataFrame
And perfect, there we go.
太棒了 我们这就开始